Jhon Ivan D. Cuaco

I am a highly motivated and skilled IT professional with 2 years of experience as a web developer. Seeking an information technology position where I can contribute to the company's growth through my software development and technical support skills. I'm excited to put my expertise in programming languages, relationship database management, troubleshooting, and other areas to use to promote and help drive innovation and enhance productivity. I'm confident that I can provide practical solutions and solve complex and technical challenges. I am capable of working both independently and in groups.

EDUCATION

Cavite State University - CCAT Campus

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology EM's Barrio, Brgy. Tejeros Convention, Rosario, Cavite JUNE 2018 - SEPTEMBER 2023

STI College Rosario

Mobile Apps and Web Development (MAWD) - Senior High General Trias Drive, Rosario, Cavite JUNE 2016 - MARCH 2018

PROJECT

Vaxsched Website — *Thesis Capstone*

An automated record-keeping and patient scheduling with SMS support for RHU Rosario, Cavite.

EXPERIENCE

Department of Agrarian Reform — On-The-Job Training (OJT) / IT Support

MARCH 2023 - JUNE 2023

- Recreated database system using Microsoft Access
- Troubleshooted printer jams, error connection, and settings configuration
- Backed up data and format computer laptop and computer
- Encoded inventory of office supplies and file records
- Managed Travel Order and Request for Vehicle request form
- Processed Purchase Request and Purchase Order request form
- Handled Inspection and Acceptance Report form

StorageBrighton, UK (Staging) — Freelance Web Developer

NOVEMBER 2022 – DECEMBER 2022

- Developed a new WordPress website directory for self-storage
- Created custom design templates for service, location, and landing pages
- Implemented ACF Custom Code Block for each page



Purok 4, Brgy. Bunga, Tanza, Cavite 4108 (+63) 967 806 1231 ivancuaco.dev@gmail.com

Age: 25

Birth Date: March 26, 1998 Civil Status: Single Citizenship: Filipino

SKILLS

Front-End Development

HTML – Advanced
CSS – Advanced
Bootstrap – Advanced
TailwindCSS – Advanced
JavaScript – Advanced
jQuery – Advanced
JSON – Advanced
XML – Advanced
ReactJS – Intermediate
Redux – Beginner
Zustand – Beginner

Back-End Development

PHP – Advanced PHP CodeIgniter – Advanced NodeJS – Beginner ExpressJS – Intermediate

Database

MySQL – Advanced MongoDB – Advanced SQL – Intermediate MS Access – Intermediate

Server Management

Apache2 – Intermediate Linux – Advanced SSH – Advanced AWS EC2 – Advanced AWS Lightsail – Advanced

Gymnearme, AU — Freelance Web Developer

AUGUST 2022 - OCTOBER 2022

- Designed custom templates for blog posts, service, location, and landing pages
- Developed backend functionalities

Sidepost, AU — Freelance Web Developer

April 2022 - JUNE 2022

- Created a new WordPress website for home services
- Converted Balsamiq wireframes into a static page
- Transformed Figma designs into dynamic pages
- Created landing, service, location, and other dynamic pages

WhatManandVan, UK — Freelance Web Developer

JANUARY 2022 - APRIL 2022

- Migrated man and van services from WhatStorage to a new WordPress website directory
- Created location, landing, and other dynamic pages
- Developed dashboard features, functionalities, and analytics
- Integrated Codeigniter3

WhatRemovals, UK — Freelance Web Developer

AUGUST 2021 - JANUARY 2022

- Migrated removals services from WhatStorage to a new WordPress website directory
- Created location, landing, and other dynamic pages
- Created dashboard features, functionalities, and analytics
- Integrated Twilio SMS, WooCommerce, and Codeigniter3

WhatStorage, UK — Freelance Web Developer

JUNE 2021- AUGUST 2021

- Maintained dashboard features and functionalities
- Maintained server API algorithms and managed data structures
- Integrated Google Spreadsheet for automatically storing EasyStorage partner company inquiry data
- Created dashboard and page templates

WhatStorage, UK — Freelance Data Encoder

May 2021- JUNE 2021

- Published self-storage location pages
- Published Removals and ManandVan service, location and landing pages

Version Control

GIT / Github - Intermediate

APIs and Integration

REST API – Advanced AJAX – Advanced

Content Management Systems (CMS)

WordPress – Advanced Roots Sage Theme – Advanced Advanced Custom Fields – Advanced Permalink Manager – Advanced All in one SEO - Advanced

Development Tools

Visual Studio Code – Advanced Figma – Intermediate Postman - Intermediate

Office Tools

MS Word – Advanced MS Excel – Advanced